Inside a forecast fragment, we're going to replace the mForecastAdaptor
with a simple cursor adaptor that will work with the
new database code we just added. This is another one
we want to make sure we're using the V4 version.
There we are. Make sure to select that in your
list. You can see we have a bunch of code
that doesn't compile. If it's a Ray adapter, let's switch
our Forecast adapter, out with new simple cursor adapter. Now,
simple cursor adapter is pretty cool. It allows us
to map columns within our database, which are in
our weather contract, directly to widgets, that are in
our list items. So, all looks pretty good, except that
it won't quite compile. Because, this stuff we're doing
to start the detail activity isn't going to work.
So for now, let's just put this away. We'll
get back to that later. We have something that compiles.
But we need to do something first. If we
ran it now, we would still get nothing. The reason
why we would still get nothing is we aren't
doing anything in onload finish. In onloader reset we might
as well complete this by doing swapCursor with null.
Our code should actually do something now. Let's try running
it. And it looks terrible. What's in the database doesn't
look anything like what's supposed to be on the screen.
We need some formatting and settings help. More functions for
our utility class. Get preferred location did look a bit
lonely there, right? To help us out, we'll add another
function to utility that tells us if metric is the current
setting. We'll add a simple function to format the temperature,
and we'll add a function to format the date. Now,
interestingly enough, what kind of date is this? Well, we've
got two options, java.util, or java.sql. In this case, we actually
want java.util, but we're missing yet another helper function.
We'll add a function into weatherContract that converts the db
date text into an actual date object, opposite to the
other Contract function. So there we have it. How we
store the data in the database is entirely encapsulated
in the Contract. So, now we've got all that cool
stuff, how do we actually use it? Let's go back
to our forecast fragment. It turns out there's a special
callback for SimpleCursorAdaptor, called ViewBinder.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Set View Binder, with a single function, Set View Value.
So inside of Set View value, we're actually going to make
really good use of those utility functions we just saw.
First of all, we'll save off as metric. If we're
using the Temperature Columns, then we just conform out the
temperature. Now that we've got setViewValue, let's put some cool
stuff inside of it. You see, that we use isMetric
when we're populating the temperature in our views and we pass
that into our new Utility.formatTemperature function. So you can see, that
having these column indices here allowed us to make this function more
efficient, and it will also help when we move into lesson five.
One of the things you notice, is that the layout height was
really, really small. That's because it was just wrapping content. We
can fix this, by telling it to center our content. And, by
setting the minimum height to the least preferred item height. This will
make things look a little better as well, a lot more like
our original layout. So let's take a quick look to
see what all of this work has done for us.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
That's a little bit more like it. Now as you can see, we're seeing our
forecast in the original way we anticipated. We
can go to our settings and we can
switch things on demand, but now we're in
that same problem I had before. We can't
do anything to get to the detail activity. Well, I'm going to have you fix that.